Hi, my name is Mark Breaux.
I've been working in men's tailored clothing for about 25 years now and I'm going to demonstrate how to tie a wider knot.
A lot of times it is used with a spread collar or cut away collars.
It gives you a wider knot.
It's also referred to as a Euro knot.
First thing you want to do when you start out to tie this tie, you need a tie that's a little thicker in its fabrication.
The liners are going to be a little heavier on the inside of the tie and make it a little heavier.
If you go with a traditional business tie like this it's going to be a little thinner and it's going to tie a narrower knot.
But, to tie this knot first thing you do, you want to start out and tie the full Windsor which, also gives you another wrap around the base of the knot and helps you get a little fuller knot.
First thing you have to do is you want to judge your length, how much you need.
You start out, you cross the front of the tie over and then you take a wrap around this first leg and cross around the back side and you go around this leg.
A lot of times with the more Euro knot, you don't pull this part as tight as you would with a normal business tie because you want it to be a little fuller to start with.
After you get that base it forms a good triangle there, cross it over and up through the neck and then down through that loop.
And that's going to tie a wider stance knot at the top here and it's going to fill up spread collar a littler bit more and then also as far as the gage you want to gage it for the over all length of the tie.
It still should drop below your belt line of your trousers.
And that's the Euro knot.